





WHO AM I?

My main programming languages and skills:

1.Python(6 years) 2.SQL(3 years) 3. ETL(4 years) 4.AWS(4 years) 5.Docker(4 years) 6.Databricks/Spark(3 years) 7.NodeJS/ReactJS/Typescript(2 years)

As a curious and detail-oriented person, I value understanding things in deep. Team work is an important trait for me and I'm always seeking for environments where there's plenty of collaboration, innovation and freedom to create and to fail.

Furthermore, in any project I work on, I focus on some key aspects. The first one is the quality of the software/data I'm delivering, they need to be top-notch. I also aim for a solid and well designed architecture, because that keep things easy to maintain and to scale. Good documentation and usability are important too, I work hard to deliver something that's smooth for users and for future developers. And, finally, observability, because it helps on spotting problems and troubleshooting.

EXPERIENCE

4/2023 - 9/2024 1 yr and 6 mos

Sr Software Eng. | Data Ingestion Platform

Nubank

on Data Ingestion team we are responsible for:

- Maintain more than 10 services in order to ingest data from a myriad of sources into Nubank's Data Lake
- Develop new data incremental ingestion platform following the Data Mesh concept of decentralisation and ownership, ingesting more than 25 bi events per day

Scala / Spark / DeltaLake / Clojure / AWS / Kafka / Kubernetes / Databricks / BigQuery

3/2022 - 3/2023 1 yr 1 mo

Data Engineer | Data Platform

Lof

- Develop and maintain the Data Platform and tooling for the Data Scientists and Data Analysts in the company
- Use Stitch ETL tooling for Data Ingestion integrating with over 100 Data Sources of 10+ kinds (PostgreSQL, MySQL, Salesforce, Pipefy, MongoDB)
- Use Databricks, AWS Firehose and Python/Spark Applications/Packages to ensure Data Governance, Anonymization, and ease Data Promotion to the Analytical Layers in our Data Lake
- Tune Spark and Cluster configs to enhance performance and cost/scalability of ${\sf ETL}\, {\sf jobs}$
- Mentor other engineers, mainly on diversity groups, on career and technical issues

Python / FastAPI / Spark / Databricks / DeltaLake / AWS / SQL / Docker / StitchETL

1/2021 - 2/2022 1 yr and 2 mos

Data Analytics Engineer

Pagar.me

- Maintained and developed the ETL flows inside Pagar.me's Data Warehouse called Tesseract (merging business rules, engineering, and data quality)
- Implemented data quality monitoring to data transformation flows
- Created automations inside the team, speeding up and ensuring quality of the main processes
- Improved the technical level of the existing systems, solved technical debt, solved architectural problems and improved system design

Tableau / SQL / Airflow / AWS / Docker / Python / Data Modeling / DataDog / NodeJs

1 yr and 4 mos part time

9/2020 - 12/2021 MLOps Software Engineer

NextCam

- Design and build the MLOps application for Nextcam's main product, improving the performance of training of new models and tunning of old ones
- Design, create, and deploy the CI/CD for all Nextcam's applications
- Improve quality/architecture practices in the Engineering team
- Develop product strategy

FastAPI / Python / Postgres / AWS / Docker / NodeJS / Typescript / ReactJS / Heroku

8/2020 - 12/2020 Backend Teaching Facilitator | Django

Python / Django REST Framework / Postgres / AWS / Docker

5/2020 - 8/2020 Frontend Developer and Project Manager

Humanoide.co

Kenzie Academy

React Native / JavaScript / HTML / SAAS / Heroku / Scrum / Agile

Methodologies / Software Requirements

12/2016 - 1/2020 Co-founder 3 yrs and 2 mos

RoadieBot

Python / JavaScript / HTML / CSS / ElectronJS / NodeJS / Agile Methodologies / Software Requirements / Arduino / Electronics

EDUCATION

2011 - 2017 Electrical Engineering, BSc.

Universidade de Brasilia

Graduation Thesis: Typography Pattern Recognition System (python, openCV, scikit-learn, dataset

composition and image processing)

Prof. Dra. Mylène C.Q. Farias

2014 - 2015

Electrical and Electronic Engineering, Interuniversity Exchange Bachelor Brunel University London

Graduation Thesis: Queue Simulation for H264 Video Codec (Matlab).

Prof. Dr. John Cosmas.

LANGUAGES

NON PROFIT

Portuguese(Brazil) - native English - proficient Italian - intermediate

I gave mentorship to 10+ professionals who wanted to switch their career to software, and the program is still open.